<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DetectionLab</title>
    <link>https://detectionlab.network/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DetectionLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://detectionlab.network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Information and Credentials</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/infoandcreds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/infoandcreds/</guid>
      <description>Domain Name: windomain.local Admininstrator login: vagrant:vagrant Fleet login: https://192.168.38.105:8412 - admin:admin123# Splunk login: https://192.168.38.105:8000 - admin:changeme MS ATA login: https://192.168.38.103 - wef\vagrant:vagrant Guacamole login: http://192.168.38.105:8080/guacamole - vagrant:vagrant Velociraptor login: https://192.168.38.105:9999 - admin:changeme  Lab Hosts  DC - Windows 2016 Domain Controller  WEF Server Configuration GPO Powershell logging GPO Enhanced Windows Auditing policy GPO Sysmon Velociraptor osquery Splunk Universal Forwarder (Forwards Sysmon &amp;amp; osquery) Sysinternals Tools Microsft Advanced Threat Analytics Lightweight Gateway   WEF - Windows 2016 Server  Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics Windows Event Collector Windows Event Subscription Creation Powershell transcription logging share Sysmon Velociraptor osquery Splunk Universal Forwarder (Forwards WinEventLog &amp;amp; Powershell &amp;amp; Sysmon &amp;amp; osquery) Sysinternals tools   Win10 - Windows 10 Workstation  Simulates employee workstation Sysmon Velociraptor osquery Splunk Universal Forwarder (Forwards Sysmon &amp;amp; osquery) Sysinternals Tools   Logger - Ubuntu 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacOS: Virtualbox &amp; VMware</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/macosvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/macosvm/</guid>
      <description>Supported Provisioners  Virualbox A licensed copy of VMware Fusion  The VMWare Desktop Vagrant plugin is $79 and is required to use Vagrant with VMware. Install it with vagrant plugin install vagrant-vmware-desktop. License it with vagrant plugin license vagrant-vmware-desktop &amp;lt;path_to_.lic&amp;gt;. Additionally, the Vagrant VMware Utility must also be installed    If you have both Virtualbox and VMware installed, consider disabling the network adapters for the provider that you are not using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 14:41:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>The pre-requisities for deploying DetectionLab depend on which platform you are deploying it to.
Virtualbox Deploy DetectionLab to your local machine as invidudial Virtualbox VMs.
 Windows, Linux, and MacOS are all supported 55GB+ of free disk space 16GB+ of RAM highly recommended Vagrant 2.2.9+ Packer 1.6.0+ (only required if building your own boxes) Virtualbox 6.0+ (older versions may work but are not tested)  VMware Fusion/Workstation Deploy DetectionLab to your local machine as invidudial VMware VMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows: Virtualbox &amp; VMware</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/windowsvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/windowsvm/</guid>
      <description>Supported Provisioners  Virualbox A licensed copy of VMware Workstation  The VMWare Desktop Vagrant plugin is $79 and is required to use Vagrant with VMware. Install it with vagrant plugin install vagrant-vmware-desktop. License it with vagrant plugin license vagrant-vmware-desktop &amp;lt;path_to_.lic&amp;gt;. Additionally, the Vagrant VMware Utility must also be installed    If you have both Virtualbox and VMware installed, consider disabling the network adapters for the provider that you are not using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Packer &amp; Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/packerandvagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 14:41:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/packerandvagrant/</guid>
      <description>To better understand the technology behind this project, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the role that Packer and Vagrant have.
A good way to think about this is to consider what would be required to build a lab like this without any automation. The steps would look something like this:
 Obtain ISOs for Ubuntu, Windows Server 2016, and Windows 10 Using Virtualbox or VMware, install the operating systems onto the VMs Once the operating systems have been installed, tailor a few operating settings to your liking Take a snapshot of each VM once you&amp;rsquo;ve tweaked the settings Now that a snapshot has been created, begin installing software on each VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Vagrant Usage</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/basicvagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/basicvagrant/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s easiest to think of Vagrant as a command-line wrapper for interacting with Virtualbox and VMware.
When running Vagrant commands, you must be in a directory containing a Vagrantfile or you will receive the following error: A Vagrant environment or target machine is required to run this command.
 Setting a default provider If you happen to have both Virtualbox and VMware Workstation/Fusion installed, it may be helpful to set the VAGRANT_DEFAULT_PROVIDER environment variable to either vmware_desktop or virtualbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux: Virtualbox &amp; VMware</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/linuxvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/linuxvm/</guid>
      <description>Supported Provisioners  Virualbox A licensed copy of VMware Fusion  The VMWare Desktop Vagrant plugin is $79 and is required to use Vagrant with VMware. Install it with vagrant plugin install vagrant-vmware-desktop. License it with vagrant plugin license vagrant-vmware-desktop &amp;lt;path_to_.lic&amp;gt;. Additionally, the Vagrant VMware Utility must also be installed    If you have both Virtualbox and VMware installed, consider disabling the network adapters for the provider that you are not using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/aws/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  Terraform An AWS account An IAM user and role for Terraform  An AWS keypair for that user   AWS CLI  Deployment Expected time to completion: 25 minutes
By building DetectionLab in AWS, we can take advantage of the pre-built Windows AMIs that have already been completely provisioned. Here is what happens when terraform apply is called:
 A VPC is created A subnet is created An internet gateway is created to give our subnet access to the outside world A security group is created to allow inbound traffic from whitelisted IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: Building your own AMIs</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildami/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildami/</guid>
      <description>This method involves using Terraform to bring DetectionLab infrastructure online by first building it locally using Virtualbox/VMware and then importing the resulting virtual machines as AMIs on AWS.
The supplied Terraform configuration can then be used to create EC2 instances and all requisite networking components.
Prerequisites  A machine to build DetectionLab with An AWS account An AWS user and access keys to use with the AWS CLI Optional but recommended: a separate user for Terraform  Step by step guide   Build the lab by following the README</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Own Packer Boxes</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildpackerboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildpackerboxes/</guid>
      <description>If you find yourself wanting to customize the Packer boxes or don&amp;rsquo;t trust running VMs downloaded from VagrantCloud, you have the ability to build them from scratch.
By using this method, you will be building the Vagrant boxes yourself using Packer. This method will take ~1 hour to build the boxes and another ~90-120 minutes to provision them for a total of 2-3 hours.
Steps  cd to the DetectionLab/Packer directory and build the Windows 10 and Windows Server 2016 boxes using the commands below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/continuousintegration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/continuousintegration/</guid>
      <description>DetectionLab is built on Ubuntu 18.04 every Saturday at Midnight UTC time using the Virtualbox provider. Results of the builds can be viewed here: https://app.circleci.com/pipelines/github/clong/DetectionLab?branch=master
The CI build process is shown in the image below:
For more context around this, please see Continuous Integration for DetectionLab</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying DetectionLab in a Different AWS Region</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/differentawsregion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/differentawsregion/</guid>
      <description>For cost reasons, DetectionLab AMIs are only currently hosted in us-west-1 and us-east-1. Each region I host AMIs in increases my monthly AWS bill. However, you are welcome to copy those public AMIs into your AWS account in any region you&amp;rsquo;d like. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:
Via the AWS Console  Log into AWS and select the EC2 service Click &amp;ldquo;AMIs&amp;rdquo; on the left hand column and ensure you are currently either in us-west-1 or us-east-1 Change the filter from &amp;ldquo;Owned by me&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Public Images&amp;rdquo; Add the following filter: &amp;ldquo;Owner : 505638924199&amp;rdquo;  You should see 3 AMIs appear: detectionlab-dc, detectionlab-wef, detectionlab-win10 For each AMI (you have to do this one at a time), click on the box next to the AMI &amp;gt; Actions &amp;gt; Copy AMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing the Boss of the SOC (BOTS) Datasets</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/bots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/bots/</guid>
      <description>DetectionLab includes scripts to install the Splunk BOTSv2 and BOTSv3 datasets and all of their recommended apps.
Installation From the logger host, simply run:
BOTSv2: chmod +x /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv2.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv2.sh
BOTSv3: chmod +x /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv3.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv3.sh
If for some reason those files aren&amp;rsquo;t available, you can access them directly in Github:
 install-botsv2.sh install-botsv3.sh  Once installed, you can query the data in Splunk with: index=botsv3 earliest=0
I recommend bumping the RAM on logger to 8GB+ if you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use BadBlood to Add Random Users and Groups to Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/badblood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/badblood/</guid>
      <description>DetectionLab comes pre-loaded with a bunch of tools, one of which is called BadBlood
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to populate active directory with a bunch of randomized users and groups, simply do the following:
 Open a Powershell console with Administrator rights on the DC host, then run:  cd c:\Tools\BadBlood\BadBlood-master .\Invoke-BadBlood.ps1 It will prompt you for confirmation, then begin adding hundreds of random users and groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/azure/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites (~30-60 minutes) Have an active Azure account. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one yet, they give you $200 worth of credit to use within the first 30 days! Install Terraform and move it to a directory included in your system&amp;rsquo;s PATH. Install Ansible. This will be used to provision the instances. Some users may prefer to install Ansible inside of a virtual environment; that&amp;rsquo;s fine too. Install the Azure command line client and make sure it&amp;rsquo;s included in your system&amp;rsquo;s PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESXi</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/esxi/</guid>
      <description>An additional step-by-step guide can be found here which also details the ESXi installation process: https://clo.ng/blog/detectionlab-on-esxi/
Prereqs (~30-60 minutes)  Have an ESXi instance version 6 or higher. VSphere is NOT required. Terraform version 0.13 or higher is required as it provides support for installing Terraform providers directly from the Terraform Registry. The ESXi Terraform Provider built by https://github.com/josenk/terraform-provider-esxi is required, but will be installed automatically during a later step. Your ESXi instance must have at least two separate networks - one that is accessible from your current machine and has internet connectivity and a HostOnly network to allow the VMs to communicate over a private network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperV</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/hyperv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/hyperv/</guid>
      <description>Intro This page contains the instruction to build DetectionLab for HyperV. Hyper-V support for DetectionLab is a recent addition and requires more testing to ensure its stability and usability.
A big thank you to @man715 for adding this in PR #513
I do not officially support or troubleshoot DetectionLab issues using the HyperV provider. You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to open issues for community support, but I will not personally be able to assist with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LibVirt</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/libvirt/</guid>
      <description>Intro This page contains the instruction to build DetectionLab for Qemu/LibVirt. This is the provider for you if:
 You are familiar with LibVirt, virt-manager and Qemu and prefer this software stack instead of VirtualBox You are willing to spend a bit more time thinkering with the build process as it is more hands-on than the official DetectionLab build process  A step-by-step guide is available at https://selorasec.wordpress.com/2019/12/03/ad-in-a-box-for-pocs-and-iocs-on-the-cheap-detectionlab-on-libvirt/#Setting_Up_Vagrant.
A big thank you to @Selora for adding this in PR #254</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting &amp; Known Issues</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/deployment/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>An unfortunate result of maintaining a project with so many moving parts is that it&amp;rsquo;s prone to have issues. Although I do my best to keep everything working and run automated build tests once per week, sometimes issues slip through the cracks.
Be sure to check the GitHub issues page for solved issues related to your problem: https://github.com/clong/DetectionLab/issues
Here are some strategies for resolving common problems:
 Issue: You run into an error while provisioning a host</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/atomicredteam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/atomicredteam/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/autorunstowineventlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/autorunstowineventlog/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/badblood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/badblood/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/mimikatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/mimikatz/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/splunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/splunk/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/sysmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/sysmon/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/velociraptor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/velociraptor/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/usage/zeek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/usage/zeek/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>