<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on DetectionLab</title>
    <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on DetectionLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 14:41:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://detectionlab.network/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Information and Credentials</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/infoandcreds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/infoandcreds/</guid>
      <description>Domain Name: windomain.local Admininstrator login: vagrant:vagrant Fleet login: https://192.168.38.105:8412 - admin:admin123# Splunk login: https://192.168.38.105:8000 - admin:changeme MS ATA login: https://192.168.38.103 - wef\vagrant:vagrant Guacamole login: http://192.168.38.105:8080/guacamole - vagrant:vagrant Velociraptor login: https://192.168.38.105:9999 - admin:changeme  Lab Hosts  DC - Windows 2016 Domain Controller  WEF Server Configuration GPO Powershell logging GPO Enhanced Windows Auditing policy GPO Sysmon Velociraptor osquery Splunk Universal Forwarder (Forwards Sysmon &amp;amp; osquery) Sysinternals Tools Microsft Advanced Threat Analytics Lightweight Gateway   WEF - Windows 2016 Server  Microsoft Advanced Threat Analytics Windows Event Collector Windows Event Subscription Creation Powershell transcription logging share Sysmon Velociraptor osquery Splunk Universal Forwarder (Forwards WinEventLog &amp;amp; Powershell &amp;amp; Sysmon &amp;amp; osquery) Sysinternals tools   Win10 - Windows 10 Workstation  Simulates employee workstation Sysmon Velociraptor osquery Splunk Universal Forwarder (Forwards Sysmon &amp;amp; osquery) Sysinternals Tools   Logger - Ubuntu 16.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 14:41:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>The pre-requisities for deploying DetectionLab depend on which platform you are deploying it to.
Virtualbox Deploy DetectionLab to your local machine as invidudial Virtualbox VMs.
 Windows, Linux, and MacOS are all supported 55GB+ of free disk space 16GB+ of RAM highly recommended Vagrant 2.2.9+ Packer 1.6.0+ (only required if building your own boxes) Virtualbox 6.0+ (older versions may work but are not tested)  VMware Fusion/Workstation Deploy DetectionLab to your local machine as invidudial VMware VMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Packer &amp; Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/packerandvagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 14:41:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/packerandvagrant/</guid>
      <description>To better understand the technology behind this project, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the role that Packer and Vagrant have.
A good way to think about this is to consider what would be required to build a lab like this without any automation. The steps would look something like this:
 Obtain ISOs for Ubuntu, Windows Server 2016, and Windows 10 Using Virtualbox or VMware, install the operating systems onto the VMs Once the operating systems have been installed, tailor a few operating settings to your liking Take a snapshot of each VM once you&amp;rsquo;ve tweaked the settings Now that a snapshot has been created, begin installing software on each VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Vagrant Usage</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/basicvagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/basicvagrant/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s easiest to think of Vagrant as a command-line wrapper for interacting with Virtualbox and VMware.
When running Vagrant commands, you must be in a directory containing a Vagrantfile or you will receive the following error: A Vagrant environment or target machine is required to run this command.
 Setting a default provider If you happen to have both Virtualbox and VMware Workstation/Fusion installed, it may be helpful to set the VAGRANT_DEFAULT_PROVIDER environment variable to either vmware_desktop or virtualbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/continuousintegration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/introduction/continuousintegration/</guid>
      <description>DetectionLab is built on Ubuntu 18.04 every Saturday at Midnight UTC time using the Virtualbox provider. Results of the builds can be viewed here: https://app.circleci.com/pipelines/github/clong/DetectionLab?branch=master
The CI build process is shown in the image below:
For more context around this, please see Continuous Integration for DetectionLab</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>