<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Customization on DetectionLab</title>
    <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Customization on DetectionLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 14:41:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://detectionlab.network/customization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS: Building your own AMIs</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildami/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildami/</guid>
      <description>This method involves using Terraform to bring DetectionLab infrastructure online by first building it locally using Virtualbox/VMware and then importing the resulting virtual machines as AMIs on AWS.
The supplied Terraform configuration can then be used to create EC2 instances and all requisite networking components.
Prerequisites  A machine to build DetectionLab with An AWS account An AWS user and access keys to use with the AWS CLI Optional but recommended: a separate user for Terraform  Step by step guide   Build the lab by following the README</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Own Packer Boxes</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildpackerboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/buildpackerboxes/</guid>
      <description>If you find yourself wanting to customize the Packer boxes or don&amp;rsquo;t trust running VMs downloaded from VagrantCloud, you have the ability to build them from scratch.
By using this method, you will be building the Vagrant boxes yourself using Packer. This method will take ~1 hour to build the boxes and another ~90-120 minutes to provision them for a total of 2-3 hours.
Steps  cd to the DetectionLab/Packer directory and build the Windows 10 and Windows Server 2016 boxes using the commands below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying DetectionLab in a Different AWS Region</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/differentawsregion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/differentawsregion/</guid>
      <description>For cost reasons, DetectionLab AMIs are only currently hosted in us-west-1 and us-east-1. Each region I host AMIs in increases my monthly AWS bill. However, you are welcome to copy those public AMIs into your AWS account in any region you&amp;rsquo;d like. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:
Via the AWS Console  Log into AWS and select the EC2 service Click &amp;ldquo;AMIs&amp;rdquo; on the left hand column and ensure you are currently either in us-west-1 or us-east-1 Change the filter from &amp;ldquo;Owned by me&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Public Images&amp;rdquo; Add the following filter: &amp;ldquo;Owner : 505638924199&amp;rdquo;  You should see 3 AMIs appear: detectionlab-dc, detectionlab-wef, detectionlab-win10 For each AMI (you have to do this one at a time), click on the box next to the AMI &amp;gt; Actions &amp;gt; Copy AMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing the Boss of the SOC (BOTS) Datasets</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/bots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/bots/</guid>
      <description>DetectionLab includes scripts to install the Splunk BOTSv2 and BOTSv3 datasets and all of their recommended apps.
Installation From the logger host, simply run:
BOTSv2: chmod +x /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv2.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv2.sh
BOTSv3: chmod +x /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv3.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /vagrant/scripts/install-botsv3.sh
If for some reason those files aren&amp;rsquo;t available, you can access them directly in Github:
 install-botsv2.sh install-botsv3.sh  Once installed, you can query the data in Splunk with: index=botsv3 earliest=0
I recommend bumping the RAM on logger to 8GB+ if you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use BadBlood to Add Random Users and Groups to Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://detectionlab.network/customization/badblood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 17:21:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://detectionlab.network/customization/badblood/</guid>
      <description>DetectionLab comes pre-loaded with a bunch of tools, one of which is called BadBlood
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to populate active directory with a bunch of randomized users and groups, simply do the following:
 Open a Powershell console with Administrator rights on the DC host, then run:  cd c:\Tools\BadBlood\BadBlood-master .\Invoke-BadBlood.ps1 It will prompt you for confirmation, then begin adding hundreds of random users and groups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>